Guide to the Stanford Alpine Club Oral History Interviews SC1018
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Transcripts
  - Ramm-Ericson, Ulf., 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Ulf Ramm-Ericson earned his B.S., 1948, and his M.S., 1949, in civil engineering at Stanford University. While a student, he was active in the Stanford Alpine Club.
    Interview was conducted in October 1997. Subjects include the Stanford Alpine Club; fellow climbers Alfred Baxter, Rupert (Bud) Gates, and Winifred Hubbard Brown; and postwar experiences in Europe. Also included is Ramm-Ericson's account, in letter form dated February 1998, of a number of mountain climbs, including the Matterhorn with Winifred H. Brown in 1949.
    Matterhorn (Switzerland and Italy).; Mountaineering; Brown, Winifred Hubbard.; Baxter, Alfred W.; Ramm-Ericson, Ulf.; Stanford Alpine Club; Gates, Rupert Louis.
  - Roberts, Gilbert J., 1997; Transcript: 38 leaves.; Photographs: 1 photoprint. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Gilbert J. Roberts earned his A.B. in psychology at Stanford University in 1955 and his MD in 1959. He was a member of the first American team to reach the summit of Mt. Everest in 1963.
    Interviews were conducted in April and August 1997. Subjects include the Stanford Alpine Club and fellow members Dave Sowles, John Harlin, and Leigh Ortenburger; his subsequent climbing career, including the ascent of Mt. Everest in 1963; his work leading treks in Nepal for Mountain Travel (an adventure travel company); his association with Sir Edmund Hillary and the American Himalayan Foundation; the Sherpas in Nepal and the effect of tourism on their lives; and his career in ER medicine.
    Mountaineering; Everest, Mount (China and Nepal).; Sherpa (Nepalese people).; American Mount Everest Expedition (1963).; Hillary, Edmund; American Himalayan Foundation.; Harlin, John; Sowles, Dave.; Ortenburger, Leigh N.; Stanford Alpine Club
  - Tabor, R. W. (Rowland W.), 1997; Transcript: 46 leaves.; Photographs: 4 photoprints. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Rowland W. Tabor earned his B.S. in geology at Stanford in 1954; as an undergraduate, he was active in the Stanford Alpine Club, holding the office of president in the 1952/53 year. He is the co-author with Dwight Crowder of ROUTES AND ROCKS; HIKER'S GUIDE TO THE NORTH CASCADES FROM GLACIER PEAK TO LAKE CHELAN (1965).
    Interviews with Rowland W. Tabor and his wife Kajse Tabor were conducted in January and February, 1997. Subjects include Alpine Club climbs; club members Dwight Crowder, John Harlin, and Dave Sowles; Tabor's work with the U.S.G.S.; his experiences in the Cascade and Olympic mountains; and student antics such as climbing Hoover Tower and exploring the steam tunnels. Also included is Rowland Tabor's essay "The Recounting of Our Night of Terror on Lower Brother," 1996, written for Betsy Crowder's 70th birthday.
    Cascade Range.; Mountaineering; United States. Geological Survey.; Tabor, Kajse.; Stanford Alpine Club; Sowles, Dave.; Crowder, Betsy; Harlin, John; Crowder, D.F. (Dwight Farnsworth)
  - Van Dyke, Russell, MD., 1997 Dec (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Interview was conducted by phone. Subjects are the members and activities of the Stanford Alpine Club. Also included are two pieces written by Van Dyke: "Memories of the Stanford Alpine Club, 1967-1971," 1998, and "Memories of Camp Unalayee," 1993; Unalayee was a children's camp in northern California run by the Society of Friends.
    Russell Van Dyke, professor at Tulane University Medical School, earned his A.B. in biological sciences at Stanford University in 1971; while an undergraduate, he was president of the Stanford Alpine Club for two years.
    Mountaineering; Stanford Alpine Club; Camp Unalayee.
  - Vogel, Beatrice R., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Subjects include the Stanford Alpine Club, its women members, climbs in Yosemite, and making her own pitons in the Stanford metal shop.
    Bea Vogel earned her B.S. in mathematics at Stanford in 1952; she was active in the Stanford Alpine Club.
    Women college students -- California -- Stanford.; Mountaineering; Stanford Alpine Club
  - Weicker, Theodore, III., 1997 May; Transcript: 11 leaves.; Photographs: 3 photoprints. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Theodore Weicker III earned his B.S. in physics at Stanford in 1953; as an undergraduate, he was active in the Stanford Alpine Club.
    Subjects include Alpine Club climbs and fellow members Dave Sowles and Nick Clinch; climbing equipment and training; his post-Stanford climbs; and a brief mention of caving trips with Stanford Grotto, a chapter of the American Speleological Society.
    Mountaineering; National Speleological Society. Stanford Grotto.; Sowles, Dave.; Stanford Alpine Club; Weicker, Theodore, III.; Clinch, Nicholas